Grizzly bears, which may grow to about 2.5 m long and weigh over 400 kg, occupy a conflicted corner of the American psyche — we revere them even as they give us frightening dreams.
灰熊体长可达约2.5米，体重可超过400千克，它们在美国人的内心深处占据着一个充满矛盾的角落——我们一面敬畏它们，一面又被它们吓得做噩梦。
Ask the tourists from around the world that flood into Yellowstone National Park what they most hope to see, and their answer is often the same: a grizzly bear.
问问那些从世界各地涌入黄石国家公园的游客最希望看到什么，他们的回答往往是一样的：灰熊。
“Grizzly bears are re-occupying large areas of their former range,” says bear biologist Chris Servheen.
“灰熊正在重新占据它们以前活动范围内的大片区域，”熊类生物学家克里斯·瑟文说。
As grizzly bears expand their range into places where they haven’t been seen in a century or more, they’re increasingly being sighted by humans.
随着灰熊把活动范围扩展到一个世纪甚至更久都不见其踪影的地方，人们越来越多地目击到它们。
The western half of the U.S. was full of grizzlies when Europeans came, with a rough number of 50,000 or more living alongside Native Americans.
欧洲人到来时，美国西半部到处都是灰熊，粗略估计有5万只甚至更多，与美洲原住民比邻而居。
By the early 1970s, after centuries of cruel and continuous hunting by settlers, 600 to 800 grizzlies remained on a mere 2 percent of their former range in the Northern Rockies.
到20世纪70年代初，在遭受定居者几个世纪残酷而持续的猎杀之后，仅剩600到800只灰熊，分布在北落基山脉一带，所占区域只有它们以前活动范围的2%。
In 1975, grizzlies were listed under the Endangered Species Act.
1975年，灰熊被列入《濒危物种法》的保护名录。
Today, there are about 2,000 grizzly bears in the lower 48 states.
如今，美国本土48个州约有2000只灰熊。
Their recovery has been so successful that the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service has twice attempted to delist grizzlies, which would loosen legal protections and allow them to be hunted.
灰熊恢复得如此成功，以至于美国鱼类及野生动植物管理局已两次试图将其从保护名录中除名，此举会放松对灰熊的法律保护，并允许人们猎杀它们。
Both efforts were overturned due to lawsuits from conservation groups.
这两次尝试都因自然保护组织提起的诉讼而被推翻。
For now, grizzlies remain listed.
目前，灰熊仍在保护名录之中。
Obviously, if precautions aren’t taken, grizzlies can become troublesome, sometimes killing farm animals or walking through yards in search of food.
显然，如果不采取预防措施，灰熊可能会变得令人头疼，有时会咬死家畜，或者为了寻找食物而穿过人们的院子。
If people remove food and attractants from their yards and campsites, grizzlies will typically pass by without trouble.
如果人们把食物和引诱物从院子和营地里清走，灰熊通常只是经过，不会惹麻烦。
Putting electric fencing around chicken houses and other farm animal quarters is also highly effective at keeping grizzlies away.
在鸡舍和其他家畜圈舍周围安装电围栏，也能非常有效地让灰熊远离。
“Our hope is to have a clean, attractant-free place where bears can pass through without learning bad habits,” says James Jonkel, a longtime biologist who manages bears in and around Missoula.
“我们希望有一个干净、没有引诱物的地方，让熊可以穿行而过，而不会养成坏习惯，”詹姆斯·琼克尔说，他是一位从业多年的生物学家，负责管理米苏拉及其周边地区的熊。